Saloni Kyal

salonikyal30@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/saloni-kyal-1b839b121

github.com/salonikyal

My major area of interest is Mobile and Web Application Development, however diverse opportunities that allow me to leverage my creativity and skills excites me. Being astute and industrious, I aim to gain international experience and implement my vision by incorporating new technologies in my work.

Work Experience

Mar 2021 – Present Research Associate

Centro Euro-Mediterraneo sui Cambiamenti Climatici (CMCC), Italy

Developing web applications and their respective technical documentation for

research projects mainly using React technologies.

Oct 2020 – Mar 2021 Researcher

6 months Politecnico Di Milano, Italy

Worked as a software engineer in European Union research project (<u>Sodalite.eu</u>), mainly involved in managing a parsing component that parses file from JSON to TOSCA YAML using Python, Docker, Swagger REST API, and Ansible technologies, along with an active role in paper publication for the systematic literature of Sodalite

Dec 2017 - Apr 2018 Android Developer and Database Manager

5 months AdMyBin, India – Green Clean Media Works (Internship)

Developed an app which manages waste in a smarter way by processing no. of people

watching ads and waste level received from sensors installed in smart bins.

Jul 2016 - Apr 2017 Android Developer

11 months Campus Karma – Campus Social Networking Website of India (Internship)

Developed a mobile app which can be used as a platform by university students to post blogs or share information about technical fests, hackathon, and cultural events.

Skills

Computer Proficiency*

*Involved in atleast one project using each of the mentioned skills. Proficiency level is color-coded.

Programming Languages

Java	HTML	CSS	JavaScript
Rest API	XML	JSON	Python
Typescript	jQuery	PHP	WebGL

Tools/Platforms

Android Studio	Visual Studio	Eclipse
IntelliJ IDEA	Latex	Git
Flutter	Unity	Xampp

Technology acquaintance

React	Agile/Scrum	App Development
Angular	Virtual Reality	Machine Learning
Artificial Intelligence	Computer Graphics	Model Identification

Proven Soft Skills: Collaboration, Leadership, Creativity, Organized, Patience.

Education

2018 – 2020 Master of Science in Computer Science & Engineering

Politecnico Di Milano – Milan, Italy

• Thesis: Mobile Application Development: Analysis of Application Types & Tools Supervisor: Prof. Elisabetta Di Nitto [PDF]

• Score: 95/110

2014 – 2018 Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science & Engineering

Techno India University, West Bengal – Kolkata, India

• CGPA: 9.43/10

Projects

Bumpy: Cycling Advocacy (Cyclist's Union of Croatia)

Distributed software development project using Scrum

A mobile app to gather GNSS data from cyclists that identifies and report road issues to the backend for data analysis and storage in order to display road quality in a map over web and mobile interface.

VeRbal

Virtual Reality game as an Android Application

A game for children to learn linguistic skills and accomplish picture matching and verbal training made using Unity(C#) and Google-VR SDK by applying eye-gazing technique on 3D models and live game streaming on a website with game-controls to be monitored by a guardian/teacher.

Drone Simulator

Computer graphics project using HTML-5, WEBGL, and 3D assets

A drone simulation game that controls the flight of the drone over the 3D landscape/terrain with keyboard controls implemented with different lightings and characterized by shaders.

Argentina Tourism (LA ARGENTINE TURISMO)

Web Designing and Development using PHP and MySQL

Apart from all the usual features of a tourism website, to explore the tourist spots and accommodations, discover the modes of transportation and book them, the main attraction is the information of local events and weekly markets, and to get a virtual 360° tour of Argentina.

Achievements/Certifications

- Team Leader for a geographically distributed software development project- Bumpy using scrum method.
- Volunteered at Indian Association of Northern Italy for traditional Indian events.
- Certificate of Achievement for the 2nd prize in E-weekend Hackathon Mozilla.
- Certificate of Excellence for achieving the 3rd position in Hello Web Hackathon Facebook.
- Web Development using PHP with MySQL course completion at WebTek Labs, India.
- Android Development and Advanced Java course Completion at Blue Copper Technologies, India.
- Scored AIR 294 in IEO (Indian Engineering Olympiad).
- Worked as an Event Coordinator of Vivarta- Tech Fest of TIU.
- Certificate of Participation in Infocom Hackstars Workshop.

Personal Information

Languages Known: English, Hindi, Bengali, and Italian (Learning)

Hobbies: Cooking, dancing, travelling, introspecting